{"tossups": [{"question": "In one compound, this number of fluorine atoms orient themselves around a central xenon atom in an octahedral geometry. Ca2+ forms this many bonds with three molecules of the polydentate ligand, EDTA. The Wurtz reaction can be used to create a cyclic compound with this many (*) carbon atoms, and that compound can be found in \u201cboat\u201d and \u201cchair\u201d conformations. This is the number of carbon atoms in (1,2)-methylbutane as well as the number of hydrogen atoms in benzene. For 10 points, give this number, which is the number of carbons in glucose and the atomic number of carbon.", "answer": "six ", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>six</u></b>", "acceptable": ["six"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "According to one work by this philosopher, the weltgeist, or world spirit, is impacted by the many volksgeister, or national spirits, and \u201cgreat men.\u201d This philosopher also used the term aufhebung, translated as \u201csublate,\u201d to refer to when an abstract term interacts with its negative. Along with Friedrich Schilling, this philosopher developed the concept of absolute (*) idealism, while his most famous concept consists of a thesis negated by an antithesis until the opposing forces are resolved by a synthesis. For 10 points, name this philosopher, who outlined the master-slave dialectic in On the Phenomenology of Spirit.", "answer": "Georg Wilhelm Friedrich Hegel ", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "category": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Georg Wilhelm Friedrich Hegel</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Georg Wilhelm Friedrich Hegel"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "J.R.R. Tolkien stated \u201cwe do not deny the worth of the hero by accepting\u201d this character \u201cand the dragon\u201d in The Monsters and the Critics. This character is described as \u201cwarped, in the shape of a man\u201d and \u201charrowed\u201d by the sounds of singing, leading him to begin a series of (*) attacks every night for twelve years, until encountering a Geat who had lost to Breca in a swimming contest. This descendant of Cain dies after its arm is torn off, leading his mother to attempt revenge on a warrior in Heorot, the hall of King Hrothgar. For 10 points, name this first antagonist of the epic Beowulf.", "answer": "Grendel ", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Grendel</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Grendel"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An improvised car known as the \u201cdeath special\u201d was used by the Baldwin-Felts Agency to kill workers in this industry. A union in this industry broke away from the CIO in 1940 and was led by John L. Lewis. A company in this industry led by John D. Rockefeller Jr. was targeted by that union and the organizer (*)\u201cMother Jones\u201d for a strike ended by the Ludlow Massacre. Workers in this industry were often not paid for laying track, as they were paid based on tonnage collected  This industry was popular in the Lackawanna Valley of Pennsylvania, as well as West Virginia and Appalachian Kentucky. For 10 points, name this industry that extracts a rock used as fuel.", "answer": "coal mining (prompt on mining but do not accept or prompt on other fields of mining) ", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>coal mining</u></b>", "acceptable": ["coal mining"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "prompt on mining but do not accept or prompt on other fields of mining"}, {"question": "With TGF-beta, this compound promotes the development of regulatory T cells. Deficiency of this compound can cause xerosis of the conjunctiva and buildup of keratin in Bitot\u2019s spots, while excessive consumption of it can lead to (*) discoloration of the skin. An isoprenoid chain is attached to a beta-ionone ring in a retinyl group, which can be found in all forms of this compound, including retinol and beta-carotene. Golden rice was developed to counter deficiency in, for 10 points, what vitamin necessary to vision and found in carrots?", "answer": "Vitamin A ", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Vitamin A</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Vitamin A"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The opening \u201callegro\u201d movement of this piece begins with two ritornellos that are imitated by two competing violins also mimicking birdcalls. High, quick scales by the solo violin represent lightning and a tremolo by the orchestra evokes (*) thunder in this work, in which a viola represents a dog barking. A sleeping goatherd and chattering teeth are also imitated in this work included as part of The Contest Between Harmony and Invention. For 10 points, name this set of violin concerti, including \u201cSpring\u201d and \u201cSummer,\u201d all by Antonio Vivaldi.", "answer": "The Four Seasons (accept Spring or Primavera before mention) ", "subcategory": "Music", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Four Seasons</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Four Seasons"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Spring or Primavera before mention"}, {"question": "One artist depicted a tree-lined street filled with carriages from the same window in this city in separate day and night paintings. Marc Chagall depicted a man with two faces and a cat with the face of a man in a painting of this city \u201cthrough the window.\u201d In another painting of this city, a woman in a fur coat and a man in a bow tie and top hat share an (*) umbrella while walking down a cobbled street. Gustave Caillebotte depicted a street in this city on a \u201crainy day.\u201d For 10 points, name this capital city depicted in Camille Pisarro paintings The Place du Havre and The Boulevard Montmartre at Night.", "answer": "Paris ", "subcategory": "Painting", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Paris</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Paris"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In the second part of this book, the protagonist returns home after contracting bronchitis, and spends two months living on the street after being accused of stealing a brooch. That character in this book attempts suicide and marries an art student, but files for divorce and is advised to leave for Europe. Uncle (*) Anoosh is arrested for his Communist beliefs in this book, during which a missile destroys the Baba Levy\u2019s apartment. A family in this book secretly consumes alcohol during a war with Iraq, before sending their daughter to Vienna. For 10 points, name this autobiographical graphic novel by Iranian author Marjane Satrapi.", "answer": "Persepolis (accept Persepolis: The Story of a Childhood or Persepolis: The Story of a Return) ", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Persepolis</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Persepolis"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Persepolis: The Story of a Childhood or Persepolis: The Story of a Return"}, {"question": "During this event, over 2,000 people were burned at the stake on Valentine\u2019s Day in Strasbourg. Alfonso XI of Castile died during this event, which likely contributed to Wat Tyler\u2019s Rebellion after wage increases were blocked by the Statute of Laborers, passed due to labor (*) shortages caused by this event. Flagellant groups were popular during this event, during which accusations of poisoning wells led to the murders of thousands of Jews. This event was initially brought to Europe by rats aboard Genoese ships. For 10 points, name this 1347 to 1351 pandemic that killed more than a third of Europe\u2019s population.", "answer": "black death (or great pestilence or great mortality or great plague; accept black plague; prompt on bubonic plague) ", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>black death</u></b>", "acceptable": ["black death"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or great pestilence or great mortality or great plague; accept black plague; prompt on bubonic plague"}, {"question": "Description Acceptable.  Shabad Kirtan and Paath are performed in these buildings, in which a holy book is placed atop pillows and covered in cloth when it is not in use. That book is placed equidistant from the two sides of the prayer hall of these locations, which is often segregated by gender. People of all religions and status are welcome to free meals served by (*) langars, community kitchens installed in these locations. People who worship at these locations obey the 5 Ks, which include carrying the kirpan, a short knife, and not cutting one\u2019s hair. For 10 points, name these religious buildings for a faith founded by ten Gurus.", "answer": "Gurdwaras (or Sikh Temples; accept any answer indicating Sikh place of worship) ", "subcategory": "Religion", "category": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Gurdwaras</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Gurdwaras"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Sikh Temples; accept any answer indicating Sikh place of worship"}, {"question": "In one short story by this author, a navy veteran gets a tattoo of the Byzantine Christ and is kicked out of his home by his wife Sarah Ruth. In another story by this author, Joy, who changes her name to \u201cHulga,\u201d thinks of seducing Manley Porter but he steals her prosthetic leg and reveals he is an atheist despite being a (*) Bible salesman. In another story by this author, the cat Pitty Sing causes Bailey to flip a car, after which he and the grandmother encounter a black hearse whose passengers include The Misfit. For 10 points, name this author of \u201cParker\u2019s Back,\u201d \u201cGood Country People,\u201d and \u201cA Good Man is Hard to Find.\u201d", "answer": "Flannery O\u2019Connor ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Flannery <b><u>O\u2019Connor</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Flannery O\u2019Connor"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One track on this album may have accidentally revealed the name of Ryan Reynolds and Blake Lively\u2019s third child, and asks \u201cIf I just showed up at your party / would you have me? Would you want me?\u201d Another song from this album describes a (*) month as \u201csipped away like a bottle of wine / \u2018cause you were never mine.\u201d Aaron Dessner of The National produced a duet between Justin Vernon of Bon Iver and the primary author of this album, which was announced by its artist the morning before a midnight release, and includes the tracks \u201cBetty,\u201d \u201cAugust,\u201d and \u201cExile.\u201d For 10 points, name this 2020 album by Taylor Swift.", "answer": "Folklore ", "subcategory": "Trash", "category": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Folklore</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Folklore"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "These materials are usually able to withstand flashover arcs, but can be permanently damaged by a puncture arc, an interior electric arc. The Mott class of these materials has electron-electron reactions that negate their small band gap, while most of these materials have a larger gap. (*) \u201cBreakdown\u201d occurs when these materials receive a voltage exceeding their dielectric strength. No \u201cperfect\u201d examples of these materials exist because all materials carry some amount of charge conductors. Porcelain, glass, and rubber are examples of, for 10 points, what materials that carry little to no electrical current?", "answer": "electrical insulator ", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>electrical insulator</u></b>", "acceptable": ["electrical insulator"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "According to some accounts, this figure and the nymph Philyra were the parents of Chiron. The \u201chundred-handed ones\u201d were imprisoned by this figure, and he vomited up several figures after he was given a cup of (*) mustard and wine by Metis. This figure swallowed a stone in swaddling clothes given to him by his wife Rhea as part of a plot instigated by Gaia. This figure used a sickle to castrate Uranus, but he himself was overthrown and imprisoned in Tartarus by Zeus. For 10 points, name this leader of the Titans, the father of most of the Greek gods.", "answer": "Kronos (or Cronus; prompt on Saturn) ", "subcategory": "Mythology", "category": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Kronos</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Kronos"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Cronus; prompt on Saturn"}, {"question": "Unrestricted access to government loans in this country led to the Encilhamento bubble.\u201cRule of the Coronels\u201d took place in the late 19th century in this country, during which the PRP and the PRM represented two powerful southern states as part of its \u201ccoffee with milk\u201d politics. The first ruler of this country fought the Confederation of the (*) Equator and supposedly declared its independence with the Cry of Ipiranga. A later ruler of this country issued the Law of Free Birth before outlawing slavery with its \u201cGolden Law.\u201d For 10 points, name this Latin American country led by Dom Pedro I, who belonged to the royal family of Portugal.", "answer": "Federative Republic of Brazil ", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "Federative Republic of <b><u>Brazil</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Federative Republic of Brazil"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The finale of the overture to this opera begins with the trumpets blaring, followed by the introduction of the percussion, and leads into a galop played by the orchestra. In this opera, one character is arrested after refusing to bow to a (*) hat, and agrees to ferry Leuthold across a lake after he kills a soldier.  Gesler is killed and Altdorf is captured from Austria by rebels in this opera, whose title character shoots an apple off his son\u2019s head. For 10 points, name this Gioachino Rossini opera based on a Swiss folk hero.", "answer": "William Tell (or Guillame Tell) ", "subcategory": "Other Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>William Tell</u></b>", "acceptable": ["William Tell"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Guillame Tell"}, {"question": "Fisher\u2019s method sums the natural log of many of these values as a method of combining results from similar tests. A curve of these values is affected by factors including study power and publication bias, while a type 1 error occurs when this value is below the alpha level, but is a false (*) positive. Data dredging, one example of the multiple comparisons problem, is often called the \u201chacking\u201d of this value. Calculated values of this statistic below the target value, usually 0.05 or 0.01, are considered statistically significant. For 10 points, name this value in statistics, the probability of obtaining observed results if the null hypothesis is true.", "answer": "p-value ", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>p-value</u></b>", "acceptable": ["p-value"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This poem asks, \u201ccurse, bless, me now with your fierce tears, I pray\u201d and claims that \u201cblind eyes could gaze like meteors and be gay.\u201d This poem describes \u201cgood men, the last wave by, crying how bright / their frail deeds might have danced in a green bay\u201d and states that \u201cthough wise men at their end know (*) dark is right,\u201d they take the title action. This poem\u2019s opening line, after which it is named, is followed by \u201cold men should burn and rave at close of day.\u201d In this poem, the author asks his dying father to \u201crage, rage against the dying of the light.\u201d For 10 points, name this villanelle by Dylan Thomas.", "answer": "\u201cDo not go gentle into that good night\u201d ", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\u201cDo not go gentle into that good night\u201d</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\u201cDo not go gentle into that good night\u201d"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Sortition, or the random selection of individuals for office, was first performed in this city, where 50 members of each of ten \u201ctribes\u201d comprised its main council. Nine archons governed this city, where a coup established the oligarchical Council of (*) 400, later replaced by an Assembly in which all adult male citizens could participate. One leader of this city added a hundred members to that boule and created the process of ostracism, while another expanded membership in its Ekklesia. Draco, Solon, and Cleisthenes led, for 10 points, what Greek city-state governed by democracy?", "answer": "Athens ", "subcategory": "Ancient History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Athens</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Athens"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The Broadway Mansions is an old, Art Deco hotel in this city, which is connected by the 20-mile-long Donghai Bridge to the port of Yangshan. Two large spheres are connected vertically by three columns arranged in a triangular shape in this city\u2019s Oriental Pearl Tower. The (*) Huangpu River cuts through this city, while the fastest train in the world is a Maglev line connecting this city\u2019s Longyang Road Station to its Pudong International Airport. Jiangsu and Zhejiang are cities near, for 10 points, what city on the Yangtze Delta, the most populous in China?", "answer": "Shanghai ", "subcategory": "Geography", "category": "Geography", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Shanghai</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Shanghai"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}]}